[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to tric
senst tasa automation
tutorial as you all know I've already
published
around 39 YouTube videos covering
beginners intermediate and advanced
level Concepts
in terms of advanced level Concepts I've
almost published 24 YouTube
videos related to trient tasa
automation so till now we have worked on
single user workspace I'm going to
publish three YouTube videos covering
multi-user workspace
concept which we will use in the
organizations for the realtime
projects so this is our lesson 40 in
terms of overall trient tasa automation
Concepts and then this is our lesson 25
in terms of advanced level
Concepts so in this lesson I'm going to
teach you how can we create multi-user
workspace till now we worked on single
user workspace but in your
organization when you are working on
realtime project you will have n number
of team members multiple team members
that means these multi- team members
need to work on one single project by
using tricentis toask that is where the
multi-user workpace comes into
picture and let us see the lesson
objectives I'm going to teach you how
can we create multi-user workspace by
using sqlite
DB and then how can you
perform check out action on different
objects of your trient
Taska and let us understand the object
checkout by other team
members and how can you do check in all
your changes in multi-user workspace and
how can you perform update all and get
latest changes of all other team members
into your
workspace and how can you perform
checkout tree and what are the
difference between the checkout at
object level and checkout at tree level
so all these Concepts I'm going to
explain
you right now so let us jump on to the
Trenta and let us first create
multi-user
workspace so to create the workspace you
need to click on create new so we
already created single user workspace
earlier how we selected
none the type of repository that we
selected is none in multi-user workspace
you need not you need to select a
repository so there are different types
of workspaces that you can create multi
user workspace can be created by using
the database Oracle MSS SQL Server db2
right these are all the different
database sources so basically to create
multi-user workspace you need to create
a
repository to create a repository you
need to have a database
instad so in the real time we use the
different databases either organization
can be used Oracle SQL Server db2
whatever the database right we'll be
selecting the corresponding database
source if I using Oracle I'll be
selecting Oracle as my database Source
or Oracle as my type of
repository and you need to provide the
schema which is optional and then most
important is connection string you need
to provide the connection string for the
Oracle database for your organization
and you can test the
connection and then you'll be selecting
the name of your
workspace and click on okay this will
create a repository in Oracle
database but for a demo purpose you need
not to have the real time databases like
Oracle SQL Server db2 instead you can
select SQL light SQ light as your
repository so when you select SQ light
as your repository you need not to
provide the connection strings schema
and test the connection so it actually
replicates the database so without
having a database itself you can create
multi-user workspace by using SQ light
okay so that's why I'm going to select
the type of repository as SQ light right
and then provide the name of your
workspace I'm going to name this as
multi-user
demo okay and then if you are using any
existing repository that you already
created in your organization then you
are going to select use existing
repository but in my case I'm going to
create a new repository I'm going to
uncheck this
option and
then you can create your workspace at
any location that you want for now I'm
going to leave the workspace
in the same
location and then click on okay so this
creates your multi-user
workspace without using database so this
concept only works for the demo purpose
but in real time you'll be selecting the
actual database and then you will be
providing the database connection
connection string okay so once you
create multi-user workspace what are the
different actions that we can perform
let us go
here
first we just created multi-user
workspace using sqi
DB now as soon as you access your
multi-user workspace it will ask you to
provide username and password so for the
first time when you create by using SQ
light your username will be admin and
password you can leave as blank click on
login as soon as you click on login
you'll be logging into your
workspace that you
created so then go and access your
project so if you see if you access your
project if you see
here all the
folders that you're seeing under the the
project are highlighted in green color
what do you mean by that that means all
the
objects
under multi-user demo project are
checked out by you okay all these
folders
objects are checked out by the user that
we just now created that means in your
system all these objects are checked out
that's why those are all you can see in
green
color okay and
then so whenever you check out the
object that particular object highlights
in green color okay so
then if you check out all these objects
means that
means any of your team member cannot
work on on any of these folders or
objects this is access will be
restricted by your team members your
team members can view the structure but
they cannot work on any
object okay
so let us do one thing let us check in
all the objects within the project okay
let you need to click on check in all
what it will do going to check in all
the objects under project so now you can
see the green symbol is no more
available that means all your projects
are already checked in all your folders
and objects are checked in now your team
members can start working on these
particular folders they can check out
their own
object required object that you would
like to work on let us say let's see now
I want to check out the execution
folder so you're going to
Simply right click and
select check out option here or can
simply select the folder click on check
out as soon as you click on checkout
this particular execution folder shows
you in green color that means now you
can start working on this
folder
and then checking the changes so before
you go to the checking the changes what
about objects checked out by other team
let's assume if test case folder is
checked checked out by other team team
member then what happens if this folder
is checked out by other team member this
particular symbol that what you are
seeing here right you're seeing in green
color you will see the symbol same
symbol in red color that means this test
case folder is being checked out by
other team member if you are seeing red
color symbol that means you cannot work
on this folder because you another team
member is checked
out you understand right
now let us say I want to check out the
folder test case simply right click and
click on check out as soon as you click
on
checkout can start working on it let me
check in this now I'll tell you what
happens what is the difference so when I
see now when I right click on this test
case folder now I don't see any options
I don't see creation of test case I
don't see creation of folder I don't see
any options available because this test
case folder is not checked out because
this is your multi-user workspace you
need to check out the folder to start
working on it so as soon as I check out
this folder now you can see all the
options is now green
color right click now now I can create
the folder I can create my test case I
can create the library folders so that
means all the options that are available
now so now let me create a new test
case test
case
one let me create another test
case sorry let me create another dise
delete this folder I want to create
another test
case test
case two so I have created two test
cases now I can start working on this
particular test
case I I can create test configurations
I can create duplicate folders I can
create if statements whatever I want I
can do
it so here now check in all let me check
in all now let us understand check out
and difference between check out and
checkout tree okay so let's say I want
to check out this I'm going to select
this folder I'm just selecting
checkout so this means this this checks
out only the folder that you selected
this is not checking out all the objects
under this folder right you don't see
green color symbol here let's say I want
to perform checkout tree at test case
level test case folder now if I see here
if I click on check out tree what
happens it checks out the folder and
also it is going to check out the test
cases under this folder that means if
you perform check checkout
tree it checks out all the objects under
the folder if you perform check out that
means it's going to check out the object
only object that you selected it's not
going to check out the children's of
particular object okay that's the
difference between checkout and checkout
Tre okay so now you understand how can
you check in so we created the test
cases under test case folder and as soon
as you check in the
changes now your other team members will
see the newly created test
cases whatever the changes changes that
you performed in your local system you
created the new test cases test case one
and test case 2 earlier these test cases
were not in the workspace or in the
project but you created in your local
system and and then you simply clicked
on check in all now the newly created
test cases can be seen by other team
members
also okay so that is done and
then so if as soon as you check in the
newly created test
cases if the newly created changes are
the newly changes done by other team
members if you want to get those changes
what you need to do you need to perform
update all so that you can get all the
latest changes done by your team members
so generally whenever you come to office
in the morning right you should not
start working on the project without
performing update all
function
because probably previous day lot of
other team members might have done lot
of changes to the project that's why in
the morning you just need to perform
update all as soon as I click on update
all it brings you all the changes done
by your team members for this particular
project that means you will get all the
latest changes to your local repository
into your local system and then you can
start checking out your corresponding
module that you would like to work on
let's say I updated all now I got all
the changes done by your team members
now you can simply right click and then
perform checkout Tre or check out
because these two test test cases
belongs to me I want to work on these
two test cases I don't want to give any
option to check out by other team
members that's why as soon as I come for
the day I'm going to perform checkout
tree and then start working on these
test cases so at end of the day once I
complete my changes I'm going to perform
checkin all okay so you understand how
can you check out objects at tree level
at only single object level and how can
you perform perform the changes whatever
you did how can you perform the checkin
so that all the changes you have done at
your local will be checked in so that
all your team members can see all latest
changes done by you and also we have
seen how can you get the latest
changes done by your other team
members by using update all function and
we have seen the difference between
checkout tree and checkout
function if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your
queries hope you all understand the
concepts of creating multi-user
workspace in any
Organization for your real-time projects
and you also understand how can you
perform different multi-user actions
like checking all your changes to the
workspace repository and then how can
you check out any component of your
trient tasa so that you can start
working on the corresponding component
or test case or module and then how can
you use the action update all to get the
latest changes done by your team members
for your
Repository please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank
[Music]
you